(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-05T23:33:05.142480",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Otonose Kanade Birthday Live 2026 In Progress
飛行艇
Hikoutei (Airship)
どんな夢を見に行こうか
What kind of dream shall we go see?
ただ正しさばかりに恐れおののかないで
Don't tremble in fear of righteousness alone
自由自在に飛び回って
Fly around freely
ステップ・バイ・ステップ
Step by step
ビートを刻んで
Beat the rhythm
果てのないパーティーを
This endless party...
続けようか
...shall we continue?
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump on this era
今夜この街を飛び立って
Fly out of this town tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the big sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump on this wind
今夜台風の目となって
Become the eye of the typhoon tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the big sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
代わり映えがしない日常の
In a corner of daily life that never changes...
片隅で無邪気に笑っていられたらいいよな
...if we could laugh innocently, that'd be nice
無意味な旅を
This meaningless journey...
続けようか
...shall we continue?
ワン・バイ・ワン
One by one
一歩ずつでいいさ
A step at a time is fine
歓声も罵声も
Both cheers and jeers
呑み込んで
Swallow them up
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump on this era
今夜愚かな杭となって
Become a foolish stake tonight
過ちを恐れないで
Don't be afraid of mistakes
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump on this wind
今夜名も無き風となって
Become a nameless wind tonight
清濁を併せ呑んで
Swallow up both pure and impure
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
大雨降らせ
Let the heavy rain fall
大地震わせ
Make the earth shake
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ
Shake your life
大雨降らせ
Let the heavy rain fall
大地震わせ
Make the earth shake
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ
Shake your life
大雨降らせ
Let the heavy rain fall
大地震わせ
Make the earth shake
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ
Shake your life
大雨降らせ
Let the heavy rain fall
大地震わせ
Make the earth shake
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past
明日を担え
Carry tomorrow
命揺らせ
Shake your life
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump on this era
今夜この街を飛び立って
Fly out of this town tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the big sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
この風に飛び乗って
Jump on this wind
今夜台風の目となって
Become the eye of the typhoon tonight
大空を飛び回って
Fly around the big sky
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
貴女の期待に飛び乗って
Jump on your expectations
今夜この羽根で飛びたくて
I want to fly with these wings tonight
この大空を飛び立ちたくて
I want to fly out into this big sky
命生まれ 命生まれ
Life is born, life is born
この風に飛び乗って
Jump on this wind
今夜名も無き風となって
Become a nameless wind tonight
清濁を併せ呑んで
Swallow up both pure and impure
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life
Yeah!
泡に乗って 海を越え
Carried by the foam across the sea,
季節をまた 連れてくる
bringing the seasons once again.
貝殻に 耳澄ます
I listen closely to a seashell,
静寂にも 声は探す
searching for a voice even in the silence.
教えておくれ
Please tell me,
この風はどこから吹いているの
where is this wind blowing from?
そこにいるの
Are you there?
時間よどうか待って 僕だけが祈っている
Time, please wait... I am the only one praying.
生まれる前に 出会っていたよ
We had already met before we were born.
寄せては返す 足跡も消して
The waves rise and fall, erasing even our footprints.
近づくほどに 遠ざかるあなた
The closer I get, the further away you seem.
ヴィーナス 風にしたためた歌
Venus, this song written on the wind...
責められるなら身を引きたい
If I am to be blamed, I'd rather step away,
もの言わぬ貝でありたい 焦がれている
I want to be a silent shell... I am yearning.
待っている
I'm waiting.
絶やさぬ人になりたい
I want to be someone who keeps things alive,
底知れぬ愛を知りたい 待っている
I want to know a boundless love... I'm waiting,
すがっている
and clinging.
雨なくば花は咲かない
Without rain, flowers cannot bloom.
名残り風に揺れ別れ去っていく
Swaying in the lingering wind, parting and leaving...
誘っていく
guiding the way.
あなたが誰か知らない
I don't know who you are,
のに触れずにいられない去っていく
yet I cannot help but touch you as you leave...
拾っていく
gathering up
欠片
the fragments.
夢に明け暮れ
Living in dreams day after day,
命も秤にかけたまま
with my life still hanging in the balance,
置いてゆくの
leaving it behind.
薄れるよう願って 幸せを祈っている
Wishing for it to fade, I pray for happiness...
眠れるように
So that I can sleep,
握っては目覚め 大人になれば
I grasp and then awaken, and once I grow up,
ざわめきも消えて 息づくほどに
the commotion will fade, and to the point of gasping,
遠のいてゆくもの
it drifts further away.
ヴィーナス いつか思い出す
Venus, I will remember it someday.
生まれる前に 出会っていたよ
We had already met before we were born.
寄せては返す 足跡も消して
The waves rise and fall, erasing even our footprints.
近づくほどに 遠ざかるあなた
The closer I get, the further away you seem.
ヴィーナス 風にしたためた歌
Venus, this song written on the wind...
背が伸びた頃 ねえきっと会いましょう
When I've grown taller, let us surely meet.
砂に埋めた涙も還して
Returning even the tears buried in the sand,
生まれ変われど もう一度あなたの
even if I'm reborn, once more to your...
ヴィーナス 微笑みと生きていたい
Venus, I want to live with your smile.
ヴィーナス 巡るあたたかな音
Venus, the warm sound coming around...
はい
Phew...
ということで始まりました！
And with that, we've begun!
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026！
Otonase Kanade Birthday Celebration 2026!
見に来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to watch!
フーフー！
Woohoo!
ちょっと駆け足でね、2曲お届けしましたが
I performed two songs in quick succession,
いかがでしたでしょうか？
but how did you like them?
たくさんコメント、パチパチありがとう！
Thank you so much for all the comments and claps!
見えてるよ！ありがとう！
I can see you! Thank you!
はあ...
Haa...
そしてね、ハッシュタグ、えーこちら
And also, the hashtag, um, this one...
画面にも出ているんですが
It's on the screen as well...
「音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026」でいっぱいポストしてください！
Please post a lot with '#音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026'!
ちょっとこの配信が終わったらエゴサーチをするなり
Once this stream is over, I'll do some ego-searching
いっぱいね、見に行くので
and go see a lot of them.
感想とか、ここが良かったよーとか呟いてくれたら
I'd be so happy if you tweeted your thoughts,
とっても嬉しいです！
or which parts you liked!
ハッピーバースデーありがとう！
Thank you for the "Happy Birthday" wishes!
ふー...
Phew...
えー、こちらの配信ですね、あのタイトル
So, the title of this stream, the live concert title,
ライブのタイトル「In Progress」というタイトルになっています
the live show title is "In Progress."
ちょっとね、どういう意味かなーって
I think you guys made a lot of guesses
お前らいっぱい推測してくれたと思うんですが
as to what it means,
が、だいたい合ってました！
but you were mostly correct!
すごい！
Amazing!
こちらのタイトルですね、こちらの英語には「未完成」という...
This title, in English, has the meaning of "incomplete"...
...という意味が含まれていまして
...and that meaning is included.
奏の、何だろうな、今の未完成ながら進むというスタンスをこのライブでお見せできればなと思います！
I hope to show Kanade's stance of moving forward even while incomplete in this live performance!
はい！
Yes!
ちょっとまだ自分にこう何だろう、完全に満足しきっていないけど、
I'm still not completely satisfied with myself yet, but...
まだまだ止まらず今に安堵せず進んでいくぞっていうそういう意味を込めてのインプログレスっていうタイトルにさせていただきました！
I decided to name it "In Progress" with the meaning of not stopping, not resting on my laurels, and continuing to move forward!
はーい。ちょっとね、えー、駆け足で紹介していったということで、
Yes. Since I introduced it in a bit of a rush...
奏、ちょっとお水飲んでいきたいんですけど、ダンサーさんたち場を繋いでもらえたりしますかね？
Kanade would like to go drink some water, so dancers, could you please fill the time for me?
無理！
Impossible!
無理！？あははは！無理じゃない！やるんだよ！
Impossible!? Ahahaha! It's not impossible! You have to do it!
はい、お願いします！なんか面白い動きとか、いっぱいお願いします！
Yes, please! Please show us lots of funny moves!
くっ...なんの動きですか？これ
Ah... what kind of movement is this?
内緒？あはは！
A secret? Ahaha!
え、ちょっとパワハラ奏みたいになってしまいましたけど、
Well, it ended up looking a bit like Kanade power-harassing them...
普段ね、奏のダンスの指導をしてくださっているとっても優しい先生たちですよ、そうですよね？
...but they are actually very kind teachers who usually instruct Kanade's dancing. Right?
はい！
Yes!
言わせたみたいになって...
I made you say that...
ちょっと今日の意気込み、なんか「うおー！」とか言ってもらえたりしますか？
Could you give us a shout of enthusiasm for today, like "Woooh!"?
頑張ります！
We'll do our best!
イェーイ！ダンサーさんたちもたくさんありがとうございます
Yay! Thank you so much, dancers!
ではではでは、次はゲストパートになります
Now, now, now, next is the guest part.
最初は誰かなー？ちょっと楽しみということで、じゃあ早速、次の曲行きましょう！
Who will be the first? Let's look forward to it. Well then, without further ado, let's move on to the next song!
party is over
The party is over
それでも踊りたかった
But I still wanted to dance
眠れないくらい
To the point of not being able to sleep
情熱の火はいつしか いつに日にか
The days of passion will eventually, come to an end
端から気付いている 焔はいつか消える
I notice from the flowers, the flames will someday disappear
ねぇ 何もいらないはずだった なのにまだ I'm so serious
Hey, I shouldn't need anything, yet I'm still so serious
あぁ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
あぁ ただ burn it up baby
Ah, just burn it up, baby
sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet, but surely, it's not that bad
あぁ give me fire, light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Ah, give me fire, light it up, baby, let it burn, yeah
燃えろよ 燃えろよ 炎よ燃えろ
Burn, burn, let the flames burn!
Yeah 千代も八千代
Yeah, through thousands of generations,
変わりもせずに
without changing,
人のなり どうか自然も燃やせよ
how people live... please burn down nature as well.
出でよ お前の火の粉
Come forth, your sparks!
焚き付けるのが仕事
My job is to fan the flames.
ガソリンとステロイド
Gasoline and steroids,
燃えるさ 醍醐味と
burning with the ultimate thrill.
火遊びはしない
I don't play with fire,
ぬるい真似できない
and I don't do half-hearted imitations.
シケたカルマ トラウマ
Damp karma and trauma,
燃やし尽くす マグマ ドラマ
burning them all down in a magma drama.
この悪なき渇き
This thirst without evil,
青い炎みたい
like a blue flame.
死は過去の一つ 隣
Death is just one step beside the past,
やがて全て一つとなり
eventually, all will become one.
love is dying
demo mada kiete nai kara
But it's not gone yet
忘れてみたい
I want to try to forget
情熱の火はいつしか いつに日にか
The days of passion will eventually, come to an end
体は気付いている 僕らはいつか消える
Our bodies are aware we will someday disappear
ゆるやかに若さを溶かして 泣かないで why so serious?
Gently melting our youth, don't cry, why so serious?
あぁ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
あぁ ただ burn it up baby
Ah, just burn it up, baby
sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that sweet, but surely, it's not that bad
あぁ give me fire, light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Ah, give me fire, light it up, baby, let it burn, yeah
Turn it up! Turn it up! Turn it up! 足らねえ
Turn it up! Turn it up! Turn it up! It's not enough!
注ぐ火に油
Pouring oil on the fire...
Sorry darling, hurry up! あぁ まだ 間に合う
Sorry darling, hurry up! Ah, there's still time.
Sorry darling, hurry up! あぁ ただ burn it up
Sorry darling, hurry up! Ah, just burn it up!
give me fire light it up baby 燃やしちゃうぜ yeah
Give me fire, light it up baby! We'll burn it up, yeah!
party is over
The party is over...
それでも 踊りたかった
...even so, I wanted to dance.
Wow! Woo!
Woo! Yeah!
奏ちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！ Happy Birthday!
Kanade-chan, happy birthday! Happy Birthday!
Thank you very much! 誕生日ガール！ Yeah!
Thank you very much! Birthday girl! Yeah!
まず、最初のゲストはカリオペ先輩に来ていただきました！
First of all, our first guest is Calliope-senpai!
はじめまして！ Hi everybody! Yo, yo, what's up? It's Mori Calliope here today to celebrate Kanade's special birthday. よっ太！
Nice to meet you! Hi everybody! Yo, yo, what's up? It's Mori Calliope here today to celebrate Kanade's special birthday, yo!
わぁ！奏の誕生日をお祝いしにきてくれてありがとうございます！
Wow! Thank you so much for coming to celebrate my birthday!
いやいや、めっちゃ緊張してた、ラップする前、「やばいやばい、できないできないできない」と思ってて...
Not at all, I was so nervous! Before rapping, I was thinking, "Oh no, I can't do this, I can't do this!"
いやいや、めちゃくちゃ、感じなかったですよ、そんな！
No way! I didn't feel that at all!
難しい、日本語のラップ。
Japanese rap is really hard.
もうバッチリ、かっこよかったです！
But it was perfect! You were so cool!
がんばりました。Yeah.
I did my best. Yeah.
かっこよかったです！もうなんか...
You were awesome! It was like...
奏ちゃんもかっこよかったよ。
You were really cool too, Kanade-chan.
え、嬉しい！
Aw, thank you!
一緒にいい感じになりましたね。Yeah!
We had a really good vibe together. Yeah!
イェーイ！一緒に歌いたかったんですよ！
Yay! I really wanted to sing with you!
私も！
Me too!
カリオペ先輩のラップが大好きで。
I love Calliope-senpai's rap so much.
あの、『Beyond the Way』でも実は歌ってみたのね、ご一緒させていただいたりしましたけれど、それ以来じゃないですか！
Actually, we got to sing together in "Beyond the Way", but hasn't it been since then?!
そうですね、あんまり機会がなくて。
That's true, we didn't have many opportunities.
でも今回すごかった。
But today was amazing.
わぁ、嬉しい！
Aw, I'm so happy!
ぶちかましました！
We crushed it!
ぶちかま...かっこいい！それ奏もやりたいけど今スカートだからできないや。
Crushed it... So cool! I want to do that too, but I'm wearing a skirt so I can't.
Yeah! Kick!
No, no, no. Stamina, stamina, stamina...
あ、スタミナ。スタミナですね。
Oh, stamina. Stamina indeed.
水たくさん飲んで。
Drink lots of water.
はい、お水飲みにいってこようかな。
Yes, I think I'll go drink some water.
Go, go, go! Yes, yes, yes!
Hi everybody! Kanade-chan mizu-time, what's up? I'm Mori Calliope.
Hi everybody! Kanade-chan is getting water, what's up? I'm Mori Calliope.
Pla-pla-pla! Abura!
できた？
Did I do it?
あぶら！
Abura!
ちょっと忘れちゃうと思ってたけど、できた！
I thought I'd forget it, but I did it!
生、生歌すごい好きだから、今回誘ってくれてありがとうございます。
I really love live singing, so thank you for inviting me today.
こちらこそありがとうございます！本当に一緒に歌えてすごーく嬉しかったです！
Thank you as well! I was so, so happy to sing together with you!
またやろう！
Let's do it again!
またぜひ！ご一緒させてください！
Definitely! Please let me sing with you again!
お願いします。
I look forward to it.
ということでカリオぺ先輩、ありがとうございました！
And with that, Calliope-senpai, thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！これから頑張ってね。Good luck!
Thank you! Good luck with the rest of the show!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
You can do it! Thank you very much! Peace!
Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
ということで、カリオペ先輩との『火炎』でした！
And so, that was "Kaen" with Calliope-senpai!
次の曲行く前に、ちょっと暑いから...
Before we head to the next song, it's really hot...
ちょっと着替えてきてもいいですか？
So, can I go change quickly?
ちょっと待っててくださいね。
Please wait a moment!
ふぅ！ふぅ！ちょっとジャケット脱いできました！
Phew! Phew! I took off my jacket!
ちょっと熱気がね、すごい！
The excitement and heat are really something!
お前らもいっぱい、お祝いありがとう、本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all the celebratory comments, guys!
コメント見えているよ！
I can see your comments!
では、早速次の曲行きましょうかね。
Now, let's get right into the next song.
ゲスト誰か、楽しみですね。
I wonder who the next guest is. I'm excited!
では、聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
Unable to speak, unable to sleep, a dream-like state...
あなたの見てる正体
...your true identity that you see.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart that no one can read...
不可思議 知りたいだけ
...I just want to know the mystery.
嘘も現実も
Both lies and reality...
どっちも真実だったの 本当よ
...were both the truth, really.
今日もひとりごと
Talking to myself again today...
なんにも無理をしないで
...without pushing myself too hard...
わたし愛されたい
...I want to be loved.
有耶無耶 サヨナラ 軽い眩暈
A hazy goodbye, a light dizziness...
あなたのいない現象界
...in a world of phenomena without you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart that no one can read.
カルテ
...chart...
自意識 溢れ出して
...with overflowing self-consciousness.
鼓動
My heartbeat...
世界像
...and view of the world...
いつも 噛み合わないの
...never seem to fall into place.
痛くて
It hurts...
毎夜 願いごと
Every night I make a wish...
なんにも 疑わないで
...hoping to doubt nothing...
混ざり 溶け合いたい
...and to just blend and melt together.
たわいない 判らない 理由 存在
A silly, incomprehensible reason for existence...
あなたと 残す 後悔
...and the regrets I leave behind with you.
誰も読めない カルテ
A medical chart that no one can read...
不愉快 繰り返して
...disagreeable and constantly repeating.
正しい夢は
Is a correct dream...
哀しい声は
...or a sad voice...
美しい 疑わしい 羨ましい
...beautiful, doubtful, or enviable?
ねえ、どれ
Hey, which one is it?
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
An unspeakable, sleepless reverie...
あなたの見てる正体
...the true form that you are seeing.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart that no one can read...
不可思議 知りたいだけ
...I just want to know the mystery.
終わらない ことはない トロイメライ
An endless reverie...
あなたと跨ぐ境界
...crossing the boundary with you.
誰も読めないカルテ
A medical chart that no one can read...
思春期 傷口 胸の内
Adolescence, raw wounds, my inner feelings...
不可思議 知りたいだけ
...I just want to know the mystery.
はい、ということで！
Alright, so...
にじさんじから、町田ちまさんに来ていただきましたー！
...we have Machita Chima-san from Nijisanji here with us!
おまえらの皆さんこんばんは！上から読んでも下から読んでも町田ちまでーす！
Good evening, everyone! Whether read from the top or the bottom, I'm Machita Chima!
わーい！
Yay!
ちまさんにも「おまえら」が浸透してる！
Even Chima-san is using "Omaera"!
もちろん知っています！
Of course I know it!
知ってるんですか！？
You know it!?
お誕生日おめでとうございます！奏ちゃん！
Happy birthday, Kanade-chan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
何なんですかその動き、やばい
What are those movements? That's crazy.
いや、ついやってちゃうんですこれ
Well, I just end up doing them automatically.
あ、やってちゃう、癖なんですか？
Oh, you just do them. Is it a habit?
癖なんです
It's a habit.
それちょっとリハーサルの時も...
You were doing that during rehearsals, too...
やめて、ばらすのやめてください！
Stop! Please don't expose me!
変な動きが出る癖なんですね
So you have a habit of making weird movements.
うん、でも今日はちょっと大人しくね、お話します
Yes, but today I'll speak calmly.
なるほど、ちょっと出てましたけど、全然出していただいて大丈夫ですからね
I see. Some came out, but it's totally fine to let it all out, okay?
気のせい、気のせいです
It's your imagination, just your imagination.
そういえばちまさんとはですね、先日、一緒に「空想列車」という楽曲の「歌ってみた」をコラボさせていただきまして
By the way, Chima-san and I recently collaborated on a cover of the song "Kuusou Ressha"...
コラボさせていただきまして
...which we released together.
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
こちらこそ！お誘いいただいて本当に嬉しかったです
Likewise! I was really happy to be invited.
そうですか！やったー！
Really? Yay!
からでも、もう、ちまさんの透明な歌声に絶対に似合うだろうなと思って「空想列車」もそうだし
From my side, I thought it would suit Chima-san's crystal-clear voice perfectly, which was true for "Kuusou Ressha"...
今回の「不可思議のカルテ」も絶対に似合うだろうなと思って選曲させていただきまして
...and I also chose "Fukashigi no Karte" this time believing it would suit you perfectly as well.
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しいです！
I'm so glad we could sing together!
本当に幸せです
I'm truly happy.
でも、からで、なんか1個気になってることがあって
But there's one thing I was curious about...
何でしょう？
What is it?
「空想列車」のコメント欄に、なんか「化け物」って書いてあったんですけど...ちまさんのこと
In the comments section of "Kuusou Ressha," someone called Chima-san a "monster"...
それは何なんですか？
What is that about?
多分別人...あの、違う人のことを言ってるのかなって思うので、忘れてください
Probably a different person... I think they were referring to someone else, so please forget about it.
わかりました！そんな、こんな、こんな綺麗な、お姉さん、綺麗な
Got it! There's no way such a beautiful lady...
そうよ、こんなねえ
Exactly, someone like me...
化け物なわけがないですよね。今コメントでも「化け物」って書いてあったけど...ちょっと見間違えてますよね、これね？
...could be a monster. Even in the live comments now, people are writing "monster," but they must be mistaken, right?
見間違いだよね。我々2人とも清楚だもんね
Must be a mistake. We are both pure and proper, after all.
もちろん、からでも清楚です、そりゃあもう！
Of course, I am pure too, absolutely!
はい、ということで、ちまさん、一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです！
Yes! So, Chima-san, I was really happy to sing with you!
こちらこそ、嬉しかった！
Me too, I was happy!
嬉しかったですね。よかったら、また機会があったら、また一緒に歌わせてください！
I'm so glad. If there's another chance, please let us sing together again!
いつでも歌いましょう！
Let's sing anytime!
やったー！言質取りましたー！
Yay! I got your promise!
やった、やったー
Yay, yay!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
じゃあ、このあとも、引き続き、頑張ってください
Well, please keep doing your best for the rest of the show.
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
応援してます
I'm rooting for you.
ちまさん、ありがとうございました！
Chima-san, thank you very much!
まったねー！
See ya!
ふう
Phew...
ということで ちょっと奏もお水を飲んできてもいいですか？
So, is it okay if Kanade gets a quick drink of water?
ちょっとだけお水飲んできます
I'll be right back after a quick drink.
あー
Ah...
まだまだまだ 続いていきますよ！
There's still much, much more to come!
次は誰かしら？ あと二人ですね
Who will it be next? There are two left.
二分の一の確率。それではお楽しみにしてください！
A 50% chance. Please look forward to it!
次の曲、いくぞ！
Here we go with the next song!
あれが世界なんて
Is that what they call the world?
誰の成れの果て
Whose ruins are those?
なんだっての悶々
What's with all this agony?
答えも欲しいのも一個てこれだけ
I only want one single answer, and this is it.
悩んだってしょうがないじゃんね
There's no point in worrying anyway, is there?
あれは夢だったって思うことにしたって
Even if I decided to think of it as a dream...
つら
It hurts...
でも全然思えないんだけど助けてよフォロワー！
But I can't think that way at all, so help me, followers!
抗うだけ若さに負け
Just struggling, losing to youth,
next, next, lucky, lucky, lucky
アーリーオー 割り切れ
Early-oh, get over it,
たらさ
then.
オーリーオー 楽なNoneとこ
Only-oh, some easy place with none.
あぁもうヤダ！
Ah, I've had enough!
なんていう新世界か！
What kind of new world is this!
あなた以外は
Other than you...
あなた以外はいらないないない
Other than you, I don't need anyone, anyone, anyone.
はらないでよバリア
Don't put up a barrier.
あるはずの何か
Something that's supposed to be there,
あったならばhappy, jumpin', yeah
if it's there, then happy, jumpin', yeah!
あなたのその手とあたしのは手を
Your hand and my hand,
つないだらもう二度と離さないわ
once we hold them, I'll never let go again.
あなたのその手があたしのは手を
That hand of yours and my hand,
掴んだら...以後お見知りおきを！my love
once you grab it... please get to know me! My love!
これで終わりなんて
Is this how it ends?
アガれないままなんて
With things still not hyping up?
鳴いちゃってポンポンポン
Crying out, bang, bang, bang.
どうにかなっちゃえって願って願って
Just wishing and wishing for things to go crazy.
ねぇ朝帰りしたりしちゃう？どう？
Hey, should we stay out all night? What do you say?
なぁもう我慢できん！
Man, I can't hold back anymore!
pain, pain 痛いってば everyday
Pain, pain, it hurts, everyday.
まゆーていけるけどなブルベ夏なんで関係ないな
I can manage, but I'm a Cool Summer so it doesn't matter anyway.
誰よりもネコ節操ないも結構
More than anyone, a cat, having no integrity is fine too.
あーしはあーしだ見ていてよready
I am who I am, keep your eyes on me, ready.
もう今日で終わらせたいなって保存
I feel like ending it all today,
リスタートできたらって
I wish I could restart.
でも無理よもう
But it's impossible now.
what's on your mind?
アーリーオー 割り切れ たらさ
Early-oh, get over it, then.
オーリーオー 楽なNoneとこ
Only-oh, some easy place with none.
あぁもうヤダ！
Ah, I've had enough!
なんていう新世界か！
What kind of new world is this!
あなた以外は
Other than you...
あなた以外はいらないないない
Other than you, I don't need anyone, anyone, anyone.
はらないでよバリア
Don't put up a barrier.
あるはずの何か
Something that's supposed to be there,
あったならばhappy, jumpin', yeah
if it's there, then happy, jumpin', yeah!
あなたのその手とあたしのは手を
Your hand and my hand,
つないだらもう二度と離さないわ
once we hold them, I'll never let go again.
あなたのその手があたしのは手を
That hand of yours and my hand,
掴んだら...以後お見知りおきを！my love
once you grab it... please get to know me! My love!
お見知りおきを！my love
Please get to know me! My love!
はい！なんと、三人目のゲストは、同じく、にじさんじから、戌亥とこさんに来ていただきました！
Yes! What do you know, our third guest is also from Nijisanji, Inui Toko-san has joined us!
まいどー、にじさんじ所属、公式つよつよケルベロス、戌亥とこです
Maido! Nijisanji's official strong Cerberus, Inui Toko here!
戌亥とこです
Inui Toko here.
いぬいとこ？
Inui Toko?
戌亥とこ。
Inui Toko.
戌亥、と...
Inui, To...
いぬい、とこ。
Inui, Toko.
いぬい...
Inui...
難しいよ！
It's so hard!
いいよ、好きに呼んでいいですよ。
It's fine, you can call me whatever you like.
とこさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Toko-san, Happy Birthday to you!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
Happy Birthday! Yeah! Nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you too! はじめ... 初めましてじゃない？
Nice to meet you too! Nice to... Wait, isn't this our first time meeting?
初めましてですよ。
It is our first time.
今日、初めまして。結構ガチの初めまして。
Today is our first time. A real, genuine first meeting.
いるの？今日ガチの初めまして... 私たち...
Is there really a genuine first-time meeting today... for us?
いない、いない、いない。
No, no, no.
ちょっと、ね、千真さんとはカオスレゾナンスの「歌ってみた」でご一緒させていただいたんですけど
Well, we did do a cover of 'Chaos Resonance' together,
本当の本当の今日、初めて。
but today is the absolute very first time we've met.
本当の初めまして。
The real first meeting.
もう今日、初めましての時、あの、とこさんが楽屋に来ていただいて、で、ご挨拶に来ていただいて。ありがとうございます。
Today, when we met for the first time, Toko-san came to my dressing room to say hello. Thank you so much.
いえいえ、こちらこそ。
No problem, thank you too.
で、なんか、その時にお弁当が奏の部屋にあったから、「あ、よかったらお弁当食べますか？」って言って、あの、「選んでください」って。
And then, since there were bento boxes in my dressing room at the time, I asked, "Oh, would you like to have one?" and told her to choose.
カレーだったんですけど、カレーとなんか付随するものがあるお弁当だったんですけど...
It was curry, curry and some side dishes...
んですけど、なんか、トコさんが...
...but Toko-san...
一言放ったんですよ。
...said one thing.
「芋だ！」
"Potatoes!"
お芋が大好きなんです、私。
I love sweet potatoes.
芋？
Potatoes?
お芋めっちゃ好きなんですよ。
I really love sweet potatoes.
カレーなのに、芋？
Even though it's curry, potatoes?
いや、お芋が好きだから。
No, because I just love sweet potatoes.
「芋好きなんだ」って思って、
I thought, "Oh, she likes potatoes,"
芋があるお弁当だったから、
and since there was a bento with potatoes,
「あ、よかった」って思って、
I was like, "Oh, thank goodness!"
「じゃあ、ちょっと芋一番大きいの選びますね」って
and said, "Then let me pick the one with the biggest potato."
奏チョイスで？
Kanade's choice?
はい。
Yes.
で、選んで。別にそれをこうあげようとしたわけじゃないんですけど、
And I chose it. I didn't particularly mean to give it to her, but...
トコさんがそれをさ、譲ってくださって。
Toko-san let me have it.
いや、それはそうでしょ。
Well, of course I would.
えー？
Really?
そんな、せっかくこれ「1番お芋大きいです」って選んでくれたら、
I mean, since you took the time to choose the one with the biggest potato...
「あ、じゃあ、これで！」って。
I had to say, "Oh, then this one's for you!"
「あ、じゃあこれで！」「譲ります！」って。
"Ah, then this one!" "I'll let you have it!"
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです、あれ。
I was so happy about that.
なんか、いろんな味あったんですけど、もう芋の大きさだけで選んでましたよね。
There were various flavors, but you chose solely based on the size of the potato.
違うよ、奏が選んでくれたから、
No, because Kanade chose it for me,
持ってったんよ、私は。
that's why I took it.
感動しました。
I was so moved.
あ、そうなんですか？
Oh, really?
そうよ。
Yes, really.
大好き。
I love you.
ちょっと！
Wait, what!
よかったらあの、今後とも何か機会があったら...
If you'd like, in the future, if there's an opportunity...
もちろん！
Of course!
なんか一緒にやりましょう。
Let's do something together again.
3Dライブもやろう、一緒に。
Let's do a 3D live together, too.
本当ですか？ユニットも組みます？
Really? Shall we form a unit, too?
もう何でもやろう。全部やろう。やりたいこと全部やろう。
Let's do anything. Let's do it all. Let's do everything we want to do.
本当ですか？よし。
Really? Alright!
じゃあユニット名、
Then our unit name...
「カルニス」で。
will be "Calnis".
ちょっと被るか。ちょっと被るか、みたいな。
That overlaps a bit... just a bit.
っていうのは冗談で、なんか一緒にできたら嬉しいです。
Jokes aside, I'd be really happy if we could do something together.
一緒にやりましょう、ぜひまた。
Let's definitely do something together again.
ありがとうございました、ということで、トコさんありがとうございました。
Thank you so much! Thank you, Toko-san.
ありがとうございました。一緒に歌えて嬉しかった。
Thank you very much. I was so happy to sing together with you.
またね。
See you!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ふぅー。ということでですね、次がゲストは最後になります。
Phew. So, the next guest will be the last one.
最後は、あの人！って、みんな分かるよね？
The last one is that person! You all know who, right?
楽しみにしてててください。それでは、次の曲行きます。
Please look forward to it. Now, let's head to the next song.
浪漫と算盤
[Title: Romance and Abacus]
主義（プライド）を持って利益（サクセス）を成した
Possessing principles, achieving success,
放した商売（バイバイ）嫌い
despising transaction let go.
学問（アカデミー） 芸術（アート） 地上（ライフ）の意味を宿す
Imbued with the meaning of academia, art, and life.
義務（ルール）解ければ理想（ロマンス）
If obligations dissolve, romance remains...
重んじつつ飽くまで
valuing it to the very end.
量子（ミクロ）割（ディバイド）は有耶無耶にしていたい<
I want to keep the micro-divide hazy.
玄人（プロ） 素人（アマ） みんな労働者（ワーカー）
Pros, amateurs, we are all workers,
賛否両論頂戴
so give us both praise and blame.
お気に召さずとも野暮
Even if you dislike it, that's unrefined.
新しい技 毎度繰り出して
Constantly unleashing new techniques,
苦しくとも
even if it's painful,
僕らは分かっている
we both understand.
あなたも同じように
Just like you,
独りで生きている
I am living alone.
宇宙（スペース） お生い（ライフ）する向かい
Facing the living universe,
仕留めたところで自由
we are free even if we conquer it.
と言うと孤独だけが待っているんでしょう
Which means only loneliness awaits us, right?
玄人（プロ）で素人（アマ）
Being a professional yet an amateur,
労働者（ワーカー）で生活者（コンシューマー）のまんま
remaining a worker and a consumer.
面白おかしくさせて
Make things fun and amusing.
喧（かまびす）しい契約（ディール） 毎度請け負って
Constantly taking on boisterous deals,
虚しくとも
even if it's in vain,
あなたを想う度
every time I think of you,
僕は許されていく
I am being forgiven.
夢と現（うつつ）を往来（また）いで
Crossing between dreams and reality.
きっとそう浪漫抱えたら
Surely, if we embrace romance,
算盤弾いて
let's use the abacus.
両極のど真ん中
Right in the middle of both extremes,
狙い撃てお願い勇気をくれ
aim and shoot—please give me courage.
疑わしい相手なら
If it's a suspicious opponent,
いつだって
any time,
自分ずっと進化したいよね
I want to keep evolving.
答え合わせ
Checking our answers,
あなたを知るほど
the more I know you,
僕は正されていく
the more I am corrected.
捨てたもんじゃない
We're not completely hopeless...
ただ生きようと
I'll just try to live.
うわああ！
Whoa!
マイクが遠いぜ。
The microphone was too far!
体震えた！
My body was shaking!
何てタフな持ち方。
What a tough way to hold it!
ロックでしょ？ イェーイ！
Isn't that rock? / Yeah!
いやー、いいですね。スタンドマイクかっこいいじゃないですか。
Man, that's great. Stand mics are so cool, aren't they?
かっこいいですよね。
They really are.
ね、おめでとうございます、本当に！
Seriously, congratulations!
ありがとう。ありがとうございます。
Thank you! Thank you so much!
これちょっとウケるね。もう一回いこう。せーの。
This is kind of funny. Let's do it again. Ready, go!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい、ということで、最後のゲストはすいちゃん先輩でした！
Alright! So, our final guest was Suichan-senpai!
はい、ありがとうございます、呼んでくださって。
Yes, thank you so much for having me!
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石、バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！皆さんこんにちは！
"A shooting star, a diamond in the rough! Virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!" Hello, everyone!
こんにちは！
Hello!
音の税の皆さんなんですよね。 あ、はい、そうです。正式名称。
You guys are the "Otono-zei," right? / Ah, yes, that's right. That's the official name.
素晴らしい！
Splendid!
音の税の皆さん、いつも「お前ら」と言われていますけれども。
Though the Otono-zei are usually referred to as "you guys."
はい、いや、もう、今回の「浪漫と算盤」という楽曲、
Yes! Man, this song, "Roman to Soroban,"
すいちゃん先輩と一緒に歌ったら絶対にカッコいいだろうなって思って。
I just knew it would be incredibly cool to sing it with Suichan-senpai!
まあ、カッコいいけどさ、生でやるもんじゃないよね！
Well, it is cool, but it's really not something you should perform live!
もう私本当に、もう私、昨日とかさ、
I was seriously... even yesterday...
「歌えるかしら、歌えるかしら」って、もう、すごい不安だったけど、
I was so anxious, thinking, "Can I sing it? Can I really sing it?"
今日合わせてみて、よかったじゃん。
But after performing it today, it turned out great, didn't it?
よかったです。
It did!
よかったじゃん。 めちゃくちゃ美声でしたよ。
It went so well. / You had such a beautiful voice!
めちゃめちゃ美声でしたよ返し。
Right back at you with a beautiful voice!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much!
コメント欄もね、めっちゃよかった、めっちゃよかったって。
Even the comments section is saying, "It was amazing, so good!"
めちゃめちゃ、相性良かった。ほら、相性良かったって。 嬉しい！
"They had amazing chemistry." Look, they're saying our chemistry was great! / I'm so glad!
よかったらまた歌ってくださいね、一緒に。
Please sing with me again sometime!
あ、そうそう。なんか二人だけで歌うの初めてなんだよね。
Ah, right, right! It was actually our first time singing as just a duo, wasn't it?
そうなんです。「パンダヒーロー」で4人で一緒に歌うってことはあったんですけど、今回二人きりは初めてということで。
Yes! We sang "Panda Hero" together as a group of four, but this was our first time as a duo.
ね、すごい楽しかったですし。 でも、またね、呼んでくださいよ、奏ちゃん。
Yes, it was so much fun! / Please invite me again, Kanade-chan.
奏ちゃんのためなら飛んできますよ。 ぜひ！ぜひ！
I'll fly right over for you. / Please do!
生でハモリという、すごい難しい難題を一緒に飛び越えられて、嬉しいです。
I'm so happy we tackled the huge challenge of live harmony together.
飛び越えたね！ 嬉しかったです！
We totally nailed it! / I'm so happy!
頑張りました、私たち。ぜひともね、アーカイブ残るしね、何回も聴き返してほしいですね。 はい、ぜひ！
We did our best! It'll be archived, so I hope everyone listens to it over and over. / Yes, please do!
はい、ということで、奏さん、この後もまだまだ続くと思いますが、頑張ってください！
Alright! Kanade-san, there's still more to come after this, so good luck!
ありがとうございます！本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much! Truly, thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
それでは失礼します。
Well then, I'll be off!
はい！ありがとうございましたー！
Yes! Thank you so much!
さあ、ゲストの皆さんにね、たくさん盛り上げていただきました、ということで、ここからはソロでですね、
Well, the guests have really hyped things up for us, so from here on, I'll be going solo.
えー、頑張っていきますよ、ということで。
Yes, I'm going to give it my all!
まだまだ、まだまだ盛り上げていきます！
We're going to keep keeping this excitement going!
その前にちょっと、準備とお水飲んでくるので、待っててください。行ってきます！
But before that, I need to get ready and grab some water, so please wait a bit. Be right back!
ここからは一気に5曲、いっちゃいます！
From here on, I'm going to perform five songs in a row!
最後には...
At the very end...
し、し、し、シークレットだもん！
I-I-It's a secret!
最後のお楽しみに、ということで
As a final treat.
それでは次の曲 聴いてください
Well then, please listen to the next song.
All Alone With You
Yeah yeah yeah...
誰かを愛することなんて
Loving someone...
できるわけなくって だけど誰かに
...is impossible, but still, I wanted to...
愛されたくて
...be loved by someone.
変わらない昨日がずっと
Even if an unchanging yesterday...
続いたとしても
...were to continue forever...
どこにも行きやしないんだ
...we won't go anywhere.
私とキミ
You and I.
神様
God...
どこへ行ってしまったの ねえ
...where have you gone? Hey,
返事はなくて
there is no answer,
いつだって
as always.
そうだよ
That's how it is.
Are you still here?
You’ll never walk alone
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I will go with you.
どんな罪も
Whatever sins we commit,
背負ってあげる
I will shoulder them for you.
道なき道を
Along this pathless road,
歩いてくの
I will walk...
あなたと
...with you.
二人で
Just the two of us.
こっちにきて購入
Come over here,
私に触れて キスをして
touch me and kiss me.
もっと
More...
めちゃくちゃにしたって
...it's okay if you mess me up...
いいんだよ
...completely.
いつか誰もが死んじゃって
If everyone dies someday...
忘れられてくなら
...and is forgotten,
今確かなものだけを
...then right now, only the certain things...
信じるわ
...I will believe in.
神様気取りの人が言うの
Pretentious people who act like gods say,
ねえ
"Hey,"
人は強いって
"people are strong."
そんなの
That's...
嘘だよ
...a lie.
Do you agree?
I will stay with you
あなたの手で
With your hands,
抱きしめてよ
hold me tight.
思いっきり
With all your might.
怖がらないで
Don't be afraid.
もう大丈夫
It's alright now.
私なら
If it's me...
その手が
Even if those hands...
汚れてしまったとしても
...have become dirty,
愛してほしい
I want you to love...
私のこと
...me.
You’ll never walk alone
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I will go with you.
どんな罪も
Whatever sins we commit,
背負ってあげる
I will shoulder them for you.
道なき道を
Along this pathless road,
歩いてくの
I will walk...
あなたと
...with you.
I will stay with you
And I'll stay with you
あなたの手で
With your hands,
…きしめてよ
...embrace me.
思いきり
With all your heart.
望めない
For there is nothing...
ものはないから
...we cannot hope for,
あなたと
...together...
二人で
...with you.
Yeah...
give it back
作詞・作曲: 中村未来
[Title: give it back
Lyrics & Composition: Miku Nakamura]
暖かい涙で
Suddenly I woke up...
ふいに目覚めた
...to my warm tears.
焦がれた
Where can I recapture...
夢の続きは
...the thread...
何処にあるの
...of that dream?
寂しいよ
I feel so alone...
please, give it back
いつになれば
When will I...
楽になれる
...finally be free?
押ししては返す
Fighting off the waves...
波に抗って
...coming and going.
白い枕に
Still groggy with sleep...
寝惚けたままの顔を
...I bury my face...
うずめて
...in a white pillow.
同じ夢を
As I wish to have...
願うほどに冴えていくよ
...the same dream again, I wake up further.
please, give it back
変わりなんていないよ
There is nobody but you.
あなたの匂い
Your scent...
思い出せない波に
...I cannot remember, as it is carried away...
攫われて
...by the waves.
夢の続きを
Recapturing the thread of that dream...
捕まえにいくから待ってて
...I'll go find it, so please wait for me.
いつの間にか孤独ぶるには
Before I knew it, I had felt too much kindness...
優しさに触れすぎた
...to pretend to be alone anymore.
沁みていく顔上げてみようか
It's soaking in, so let's raise our heads.
ひとりじゃないって信じてみたい
I want to believe that I'm not alone.
信じてみたいの
I really want to believe.
give it a shot
生まれたばかりの
In this newborn...
淡い光に
...faint light...
希望を見たの 胸が熱いよ
...I saw hope, and my heart feels hot.
手を握っていよう
Let us hold hands...
迷わないように
...so we won't get lost.
明日からまた
Starting tomorrow...
選んだ道を進めるように
...so we can continue to walk the chosen path.
敗北の少年
Defeated Boy
お前ら！まだまだいくぞー！
Everyone! We're still keeping this going!
ぶつかって
Struggling,
逃げ込んで
running away,
僕はいつしかここに立ってた
before I knew it, I was standing here.
誰もが
Everyone
憧れるヒーローに
wants to be the hero they admire,
なりたくて
wishing to become one,
でもなれなくて
but unable to.
これくらいじゃ
At this rate,
届かないこと
I won't reach you,
分かっていたのに
even though I already knew that.
敗北の少年
Defeated boy,
現実を謳え
sing praises of reality.
あんな風に空は飛べやしないんだ
We can't fly through the sky like that.
こんな夜に意味があるなら
If there's meaning to a night like this,
僕らは地を這う
we will crawl across the ground.
耳鳴りが
A ringing in my ears
こだまして
echoes,
僕に奇跡が問いかけるんだ
and a miracle asks me...
「君の夢
"Your dream of becoming
憧れたヒーローに
the hero you admired...
今すぐさせてあげよう」
I'll make it come true right now."
飴みたいに差し伸べられたって
Even if it's offered to me like candy,
嬉しくないんだ
I'm not happy at all.
敗北の少年
Defeated boy,
存在を謳え
sing praises of existence.
君みたいに眩しくはなれないけど
Though I can't be radiant like you,
こんな夜に意味があるなら
if there's meaning to a night like this,
僕らは地を這う
we will crawl across the ground.
まだ地を這う
And yet crawl the ground...
鼓動を知って
Feeling my heartbeat,
息を吸い込んで
taking a deep breath,
「僕は遠慮するよ」
"No thanks, I'll pass."
敗北の...
Defeated...
敗北の少年
Defeated boy,
平凡を謳え
sing praises of normalcy.
あいにくと神は信じないタチで
Unfortunately, I'm not the type to believe in God.
すれ違いの物語よ
To this passing story...
さようなら
...farewell.
敗北の少年
Defeated boy,
現実を謳え
sing praises of reality.
僕らは泥を傷つくばるもの
We are the ones who crawl through the mud.
こんな夜も愛しいから
Because even a night like this is beloved,
僕らは地を這う
we will crawl across the ground.
ただ地を這う
Just crawl across the ground.
あのね
You know...
Luna say maybe
あのね
You know...
I say 「私、大丈夫？」
I say, "Am I okay?"
Maybe, うまくやれるはず
Maybe, I should be able to do well.
ずっと走った 息継ぎもしないまま
Running the whole time without even catching my breath.
あっそう、終わりが来るなら
Oh right, if the end is coming,
別に寂しくなんかはない
I'm not particularly lonely.
真実は心の奥の方
The truth is deep inside my heart.
自分のことすら愛せないまま
Without even being able to love myself...
れないまま 君のこと守れるのかな
...unable to even love myself, can I protect you?
信じて
Believe me.
どうか、正真正銘のこの思いを聴いて
Please, listen to my true, genuine feelings.
私、全身全霊で歌うから
Because I'm singing with all my heart and soul.
大丈夫、世界はこんなに綺麗だと
It's okay, I understand that the world is so beautiful...
分かってる、分かってる、分かってる、わかってるよ！
I know, I know, I know, I know!
ごめんね。じれったい
I'm sorry. It's frustrating.
足りない、こんなんじゃ誰も愛せないの
It's not enough, I can't love anyone like this.
止めない、止まることは知らないの
Don't stop, I don't know how to stop.
言葉足らず、失くしてしまう物ばかりだ
With my lack of words, I only end up losing things.
Luna say maybe... 降るのは、
Luna say maybe... What falls is,
迷be, rainy
maybe, rainy.
愛せ、どんな自分でも
Love whoever you are,
Navy色に染まるまで
until you're dyed in navy.
時間はかかるかもしれないけど
It might take some time, but...
I know, 輝くしかないこと
I know, there's no choice but to shine,
ハイライト、塗り続けるしかない
and keep painting the highlights.
真実はちゃんと、言わなくちゃね
I must speak the truth properly, right?
目に見えるものが 続くと、ずっと
I want to believe that what is visible
そう、ずっと... 思いたい
will continue on forever, yes, forever.
君に、半信半疑な素振りして
Acting half-doubting to you,
心、空回り、遠回り
my heart spins its wheels, going the long way around.
最低だ、もう一回やり直せるのなら
I'm the worst, if I could start over just once more,
素直になりたい、なりたい、なりたいと願ったジレンマ
I want to be honest, I want to be, I want to be—this dilemma I wished for.
このまま、1人じゃ何もできない
Like this, I can't do anything alone.
全部、決めるのは、自分次第
It's all up to me to decide.
初めて背中をみた時に、覚悟を決めた。
The moment I saw your back for the first time, I made up my mind.
どこまでいけるのか 届くのか わからないよ
I don't know how far I can go, or if I will reach you.
臆病が そこに立っている
Cowardice is standing right there.
3秒前バックステージ 震える背中を君に預けて
Three seconds ago backstage, I entrusted my trembling back to you.
この運命的出会いは きっと、そう、きっと 偶然みたいな
This fateful encounter is surely, yes, surely like a coincidence.
多分、神様のいたずらです
It's probably a trick played by God.
どうか、正真正銘のこの思いが
Please, let these genuine feelings
君の心にちゃんと届く まで
properly reach your heart.
ここで、私、全身全霊で歌うから
Because here, I am singing with all my heart and soul.
待ってる、待っている だから、この場所を大切にしたいの！
I'm waiting, I am waiting, so I want to cherish this place!
これが、正真正銘の私 だ！
This is the real, genuine me!
大丈夫、もう怖く はないわ
It's okay, I'm not afraid anymore.
たまに つまづく こと なら、あるけれど
Though I might stumble sometimes,
1番 特等 席 で君 の 笑顔 見 たい ん だ
I want to see your smile from the very best seat.
私 だけ の 特権
It's my exclusive privilege.
見えない 未来、手探り 今日も ステージ の上 で 証明 して 見せる から
An unseen future, groping in the dark—today too, I will prove it on stage!
ここにしかない スクリーン
The screen that only exists here,
きりり
sharp and tight...
君にまだ話せてないことばかりあるんだ
There are so many things I haven't told you yet.
聞いて欲しいの あのね
I want you to hear them, you know?
今日、見に来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming to see me today!
最後は新曲をお届けします！
Lastly, I'll perform my new song!
聴いてください！
Please listen to it!
You & 合図
You & Signal
目覚めの合図
The signal to wake up
スマホが踊る
My smartphone dances
そして半分眠った瞳で
And with half-asleep eyes
心の震えは A=440Hz（よんよんぜろ）
My heart trembles at A=440Hz
今日のリズムは合言葉で合わせよう
Let's sync today's rhythm with our password
ドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥ
Duru duru duru duru duru
一歩前に レガート深呼吸
One step forward, a legato deep breath
会う前には 二度の瞬き
Blinking twice before we meet
月曜の約束を奏でよう
Let's play our Monday promise
ねえ、君と僕の合図
Hey, our secret signal
...君と僕の合図
...our sign.
もう一歩を 踏み出して
Take one more step forward,
踏み出して
take a step forward,
合わせてみよう
and let's align our steps.
なんでマンデー どうしてサンデー
Why Monday, why Sunday?
明日へ弾んでいたいの
I want to bounce forward into tomorrow.
タクトをシュッ シュッ
Wave the baton, swish, swish!
拍手をパン パン
Clap your hands, clap, clap!
ここからはすべてダ・カーポ
From here on, it's all Da Capo.
日曜日の
Let's leap over...
コーダを飛び越えて
...Sunday's Coda.
待ってるよ
I'm waiting for you.
明日よ来ないでと願ってしまうほど
To the point where I wish tomorrow would never come.
(La La La)
あなたを待ちわびる
Even the time spent...
時間すらも愛おしい
...waiting eagerly for you is precious.
一歩前にレガート深呼吸
Take a step forward, legato, deep breath.
スタッカートで二度の瞬き
Blink twice, staccato.
月曜日の約束を奏でよう
Let's play Monday's promise.
ねえ、君と僕の合図
Hey, our sign.
(La La La)
奏でよう
Let's play it.
ねえ 叶うよ
Hey, it'll come true.
私たちだけの合図
A sign just for us.
なんと！最後の曲は、
And with that! The final song was...
奏自身の2曲目のオリ曲、You & 合図でした！
...my second original song, "You & Aizu"!
パフパフ〜！
Yay, yay!
はい！ということで、新曲のジャケ写です！
Yes! And here is the cover art for the new song!
このあと、24時…えっと、21日の0時から配信開始です！
It will be available for streaming from 24:00—rather, 0:00 on the 21st!
あ、ちょっと噛んじゃいました。21日の0時から配信開始です！
Ah, I stumbled a bit. Streaming starts at 0:00 on the 21st!
もうね、すごく可愛い振り付けとなっているので、よかったら踊ってみね！
The choreography is really cute, so please try dancing to it!
さらに、この配信のあと、MVも…えっと、21日の
Furthermore, after this stream, the MV will also...
21時10分からプレミア公開されます！
...have a premiere release at 21:10 on the 21st!
もうこちらの楽曲ですね、あの歌詞もチラッと見えていたから、ちょっと気づいてるお前らもね、
For this song, the lyrics were visible briefly, so those of you who noticed...
たくさんコメント欄でさ、わくわくしていたと思うんですが、
...must have been buzzing with excitement in the comments section.
あの、月曜日だったり、奏の要素がいっぱい込められている
It's packed with Otonose Kanade elements, like Monday,
そういう楽曲となっているので、よかったらね、あの、いっぱい聴いてください！
so I'd be really happy if you listened to it a lot!
はーい！
Yay!
えっと、ということで皆さんおまちかねのグッズ情報も行って参りたいと思います！
Now, let's move on to the merchandise info that everyone has been waiting for!
MVも見てね！
Be sure to watch the MV too!
えっと、
And...
えっと、音乃瀬奏生誕記念グッズ2026！
...here is the Otonose Kanade Birthday Celebration Merch 2026!
パンパカパーン！可愛いー！
Ta-da! So cute!
配信開始はこのあと、21時20分からだから、安心して最後まで
Sales will start soon at 21:20, so don't worry, relax...
ちゃんと見ていってね！順番に紹介していきます！
...and watch until the end! I'll introduce them one by one!
まずは、こちら！デデン！「奏と待ち合わせ！ポストカードフレーム」！
First is this! *Ta-da!* "Meetup with Kanade! Postcard Frame"!
今回のキービジュアルを「奏と待ち合わせ」をテーマに
This time's key visual is themed "Meetup with Kanade,"
gomziママーに描いていただきましたので、日常のワンシーンを飾るイメージで作ってみました！可愛いでしょー！
drawn by gomzi-mama, designed with the feel of framing a daily life moment! Isn't it cute?
そのままでも楽しめるほか、他のポストカードとか挟んで別の絵柄で楽しむこともできます！
You can enjoy it as is, or swap in other postcards to enjoy different illustrations!
二つ目は、こちら！
The second item is this!
「また奏が落書きしちゃったw Tシャツ」！
"Kanade Doodled Again lol T-shirt"!
奏の落書きTシャツ第二弾！
The second volume of Kanade's doodle T-shirts!
本当に今日は月曜日！
Today really is Monday!
もう月曜日盛りだくさんです！ハッピー月曜日！
So much Monday today! Happy Monday!
ということで、月曜日Tシャツです！
So here's the Monday T-shirt!
毎週月曜日にはこのTシャツを着てね、よかったら生活してください！最高！ありがとう！
Please wear this T-shirt every Monday and enjoy your day! It's great! Thank you!
えっと、三つ目は、こちら！
And the third item is this!
「奏とおそろ！ネックレス」！可愛いでしょー！
"Matching with Kanade! Necklace"! Isn't it cute?
今回キービジュアルの奏とおそろいの、奏モチーフのネックレスです！
This is a Kanade-themed necklace matching the one Kanade wears in the key visual!
確か、デビュー日が書かれているはず！です、奏の。よかったら、
If I remember correctly, my debut date is engraved on it! If you'd like,
すごいシンプルでスタイリッシュなデザインに落とし込んでみたので
it's designed to be very simple and stylish,
普段アクセサリー着けないよっていう人も、ぜひお手に取って着けてみてください！
so even if you don't usually wear accessories, please give it a try!
そして四つ目、こちら！
And the fourth item is this!
「『明日は月曜日！w』ひょっこりぬいぐるみ」！
"\"Tomorrow is Monday! lol\" Peek-a-boo Plushie"!
いや、もうね、こちらの素敵な、もう、素敵なフリップを持った奏のぬいぐるみです！
It's a plushie of Kanade holding this wonderful sign!
画面モニターとかに引っ掛けて飾ることができますので
You can display it by hanging it over your screen or monitor,
いつでも、上から奏が「月曜日だよ〜！」ってお知らせいたします！いえーい！
so Kanade can always notify you from above, "It's Monday!" Yay!
最後に、フルセット購入特典！パンパカパーン！
Finally, the full set purchase bonus! *Ta-da!*
として、数量限定で直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
A limited-quantity postcard with a handwritten signature and foil-stamped printed message!
通常版は箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと、
The regular version comes with a foil-stamped signature and printed message postcard,
ボイスがついてきます！今回のボイスは…
along with a voice pack! This time's voice pack is...
い、色々、決意表明！
A-and various... declarations of determination!
お前らへの感謝とこれからの意気込みを ありのまま伝えるフリートークボイスになっています
It's a free-talk voice where I share my gratitude to you all and my future enthusiasm as they are.
ボイスはフルセットを購入したら必ず付いてくるから 安心してね！
The voice always comes with the full set, so don't worry!
以上、グッズ紹介でした！
And that's it for the merch introduction!
みんな、今日は...
Everyone, today is...
月曜日だね。
Monday, isn't it?
そんな月曜日のお前らには...
To you guys on such a Monday...
ドン！
Bam!
犬！
A dog!
今回は犬です。今日は月曜日ということで...
This time, it's a dog. Since today is Monday...
犬のリップ。今年ね、エイプリルフールネタを擦っていきますよ。ワン！
Dog lips! I'm milking the April Fool's joke this year. Woof!
えっと、この後メン限にてアンコールライブもやっちゃうよ！
Um, after this, I'm doing an encore live stream in the members-only section!
このQRコードはなんなんだ？
What's this QR code about?
アンコールではちょっとお前らのリクエストに応えたりするかも？
Maybe I'll take some of your requests during the encore?
このQR、あ、あ、いけないいけない。お前ら読み込んでしまう。
This QR... Oh, wait, wait, no! You guys will scan it.
このQRを読み込んだら、えっと、メンバーシップに入れるみたいです。
Apparently, scanning this QR code lets you join the membership.
うん、じゃあ見せないでおこう。
In that case, I won't show it.
うぇ〜、見せないでおこう。
Hmph, I won't show it to you!
え、見せちゃおうかな、どうしようかな〜。
Wait, should I show it? What should I do~?
はい、えっと、あはは！
Okay, so, haha!
それじゃあ、今日は本当に奏のライブに見に来てくれてありがとうございました。
Well then, thank you so much for coming to watch Kanade's live today.
全編生ライブという 奏にとっても挑戦的なライブでして 本当はめちゃくちゃ怖かったんですけど
A fully live concert was a huge challenge for me, and I was actually super scared, but...
なんとか、ポスト、Xだったり お前らが応援のメッセージを送ってくれたおかげで
somehow, thanks to the posts on X and you guys sending supportive messages,
すごく、もう緊張もそんなにせず終えられたかなと思います。
I think I was able to get through it without feeling too nervous.
本当に見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to watch!
それでは、メン限アンコールライブでまた会おうね！
Well then, let's meet again in the members-only encore live!
ありがとう！またね！
Thank you! See you later!
チャンネル登録してね！
Be sure to subscribe!
見に来てくれて本当に、本当にありがとう。
[On-screen Text] Thank you so, so much for coming to watch.
正直、すごく怖かったけど お前らが応援してくれたから最後までやり遂げることができました。
Honestly, I was really scared, but thanks to your support, I was able to see it through.
これからもお前らに向けられる奏でいられるように いっぱいがんばります ついてきて！
I'll do my best so I can continue to perform for you all. Keep following me!